Capra Press mss., 1955-2010 LMC 2228
Lilly Library
Capra Press mss.
1955-2010
Lilly Library
LMC 2228
68 Boxes
The Capra Press mss., 1955-2010, contain the correspondence, book production materials, manuscripts, galleys, printing records, and cost sheets of printer/publisher Noel Young of Santa Barbara, California.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 1986
Biographical Note
The press was founded in 1948 as Noel Young Printer, produced the first Capricorn Press book in 1969, and in July 1972 changed to its present name, Capra Press. These particular files date most heavily from 1966 to present, although some correspondence relating to Young's letter press job printing for other publishers dates from 1955.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondents in the collection include Will Baker, Clayton C. Barbeau, Peter Beagle, William Benton, Dave Bohn, Eugene Howard Boudreau, Ray Bradbury, Alan Brilliant, Edwin Brock, Andreas Brown, Lennart Bruce, Charles Bukowski, Wynn Bullock, Leonora Carrington, Raymond Carver, George F. Christians, Andrei Codrescu, Lewis Augustus Coffin, Alexander Comfort, Richard DeMille, Diane Di Prima, Edward Dorn, Renate Druks, Beverly Dubin, Robert Durand, Lawrence Durrell, Gretel Ehrlich, Clayton Eshelman, William Everson, Lawrence Fixel, Barry Gifford, Edward Gorey, Robert Gover, Gregory Grace, Gordon Grant, Blanca Nyland Hamri, Richard C. Higgins, Jack Hirschman, Rochelle Holt, Lee Hopkins, James D. Houston, Joseph Jaqua, William C. Kaysing, David Kherdian, Faye Kicknosway, Zig Knoll, Greg Kuzma, Ursula K. LeGuin, Lyn Lifshin, Sam Long, Jack McQuarrie, Hugo Manning, Morton Marcus, John Martin, David Meltzer, Jerred Metz, Kenneth Millar, Henry Miller, Bob Nash, Robert Nathan, Ana‹s Nin, William Francis Nolan, Gloria Orenstein, Otto Penzler, Lawrence Clark Powell, Carlos Reyes, Hubert Ribeiro, William J. Robson, Edouard Roditi, Mary Savage, Leighton G. Steele, Leslie Clark Stevens, Joseph Stroud, Lynn Sukenick, Fr'd'ric Jacques Temple, Carl Thayler, Jim White, Colin Wilson, and Noel Young.
The files also include a brief history of the press prepared by Noel Young, clippings about the press, and some photographs of Capra authors.
Note on Indexing Term - "Art": Included are illustrations, engravers proofs, art work, pen and ink drawings and book design material for various works.
Arrangement
The archive is divided broadly into five categories: I. Correspondence, II. Capra Press publications, III. Non-Capra publications, including other publishers' works reprinted by Noel Young, IV. Capra Press printing records, and V. Miscellaneous Capra Press documents. The contents of each series are arranged by the name of the author or correspondent, then sorted by date, and finally by folder title.
Due to the large size of Series II, its folders are physically arranged similarly to their original order, and are sorted in boxes by date, then author name. Intellectually, this series follows the same organizational structure as the rest of the collection, and is arranged alphabetically by the author's name first, and then sorted by date.
Art; Publishers and publishing; American literature; Capra Press
- I. Correspondence
  - Authors and publishers
    - Aaland, Mikkel, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Abramson, Martin P., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Akmakjian, Hiag, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Baker, Will, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Barbeau, Clayton C., 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Beagle, Peter S., 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Benson, Robert, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Benton, William, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bohn, David, 1972-1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bonazzi, Robert, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Boudreau, Eugene, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Boyle, Kay, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bradbury, Ray, 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Brady, Irene, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bridge, Scott R., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Brock, Edwin, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bronfen, Nan, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Brown, Andreas, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bryan, Robert, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bukowski, Charles, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Carrington, Leonora, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Carver, Raymond, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Codrescu, Andrei, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Comfort, Alex, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - DeMille, Richard, 1972-1977 (Box 1, Folder 26-28)
    - Detro, Gene, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - di Prima, Diane, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Dubin, Beverly, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Durand, Robert, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
    - Durrell, Lawrence, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
    - Dworski, Susan, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Easton, Robert, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Ehrlich, Gretel, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Eshleman, Clayton, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Everson, William, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Fagan, Brian M., 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Fixel, Lawrence, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Gorey, Edward, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Gover, Robert, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Grace, Gregory, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Grant, Gordon, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Gray, Virginia, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Hamri, Blanca; Hamri, Mohamed, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Higgins, Dick, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Hirschman, Jack, 1972-1981 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Hoagland, Edward, 1987-1994 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Holt, Rochelle, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Hopkins, Lee, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Houston, James, 1972-1985 (Box 1, Folder 55-56)
    - Houston, James; Haslam, Gerry, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Howorth, Peter C., 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Jacopetti, Roland, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - James, Allston, 1977-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Jett, Stephen, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Jong, erica, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Kaysing, William, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Kelly, Frank, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Kherdian, David, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Kicknosway, Faye, 1972-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Kirsch, Robert, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Kostelanetz, Richard, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Krysl, Marilyn, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Kuzma, Greg, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Leen, Daniel, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Le Guin, Ursula, 1975-1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Liddy, James, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Lifshin, Lin, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Loam, Jayson, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Long, Sam, 1972-1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Marcus, Morton, 1972-1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Martin, Jay, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
    - Meltzer, David, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Metz, Jerred, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Miller, Henry, 1969-1979 (Box 2, Folder 24-26)
    - Loujon Press, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Monsarrat, Rachel, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Morgan, Richard, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 31-32)
    - Morse, Peter, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Nathan, Robert, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Nin, Anais, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Nolan, William, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Orenstein, Gloria, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Penzler, Otto, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Perera, Padma, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Perera, Victor, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Miller, Henry, 1976-1981 (Box 2, Folder 27-29)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark, 1973-1980 (Box 2, Folder 41-44)
    - Rabe, Claire, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Reyes, Carlos, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Ribeiro, Hubert, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Roditi, Edouard, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Russell, Ray, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Ryan, Tim, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Salzmann, Laurence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Sanford, John, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - San Francisco Book Co., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Savage, Mary, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Schaefer, Jack, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Secunda, Arthur, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Scrimshaw Press, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Serendipity Books, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Sheldon Press, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Smith, Olive; Hamber, Jan, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Sommer, Robert, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Steele, Leighton, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Stevens, Leslie, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Stroud, Joe, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Sukenick, Lynn, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Temple, F.J., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Terrell, John Lipton, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
    - Thayler, Carl, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Van der Ryn, Sim, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - VanMeter, Ben, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Vinz, Mark, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Weaver, John, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - White, Jim, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Young, Robert, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Business correspondence
    - Correspondence with printers, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence with printers, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - January-August, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - September-December, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - January-April, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - May-August, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - September-December, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - January-March, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - April-June, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - July-September, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - October-December, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - January-February, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - March-April, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - May-June, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence with printers, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence with printers, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - July-August, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - September-October, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - November-December, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - January, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - February, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - March, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - April, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - May, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - June, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - July, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - August, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - September, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - October, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - November, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - December, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - January, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - February, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - March, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - April, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - May, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - June, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - July-August, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - September-October, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - November-December, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - January, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - February, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - March, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - April, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - May, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - June, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - July, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - August, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - September, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - October, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - November, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - December, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - January, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - February, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - March, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - April, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - May, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - June, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - July, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - August, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - September, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - October, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - November, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - December, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
    - January, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - February, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - March, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - April, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - May, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - June, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - July, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - August, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - September, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - October, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - November, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - December, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - January, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - February, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - March, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - April, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - May, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - June, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - July, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - August, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - September, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - October, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - November, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - December, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - January, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - February, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - March, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - April, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - May, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - June-July, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - August, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - September, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - October, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - November, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - December, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Misc, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - January, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - February, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - March, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - April, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - May, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - June, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - July, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - August, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - September, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - October, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - November, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - December, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - January, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - February, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - March, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - April, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - May, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - June, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - July, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - August, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - September, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - October, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - November-December, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - January, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - February, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - March, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - April, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - May, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - June, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
    - July, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - August, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - September, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - October, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - November, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - December, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - January-February, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - March, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - April, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - May, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - June, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - July, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - August-December, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence list, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Undated correspondence (Box 10, Folder 9-21)
    - August queries, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - September queries, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - October queries, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - November queries, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - December queries, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous queries, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - January queries, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Undated queries, pre 1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - General correspondence
    - Correspondence list, 1970-1979 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Noel Young correspondence, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Letters to Noel Young re: Henry Miller, 1978-1991 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1985-1995 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- II. Capra Press publications
  - Aaland, Mikkel
    - County Fair Portraits, Album, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - County Fair Portraits, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - County Fair Portraits, Misc., 1981 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - County Fair Portraits, MS, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - County Fair Portraits, Proofs, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Sweat, Clippings, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Sweat, Cover design, 1978 (Box 59, Folder Unknown)
    - Sweat, First draft, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Sweat, Illustrations, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Sweat, Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Sweat, MS, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 17-18)
    - Sweat, Printer's MS, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 19-20)
    - Sweat, Proofs, 1978 (Box 59, Folder Unknown)
    - Sweat, Proofs, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - Abbey, Edward
    - Black Sun, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Black Sun, Correspondence, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Red Night Valley and other works, Correspondence, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Abbott, Keith
    - Downstream from Trout Fishing in America, Correspondence, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Downstream from Trout Fishing in America, MS, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 8-10)
    - Downstream from Trout Fishing in America, Photos and misc. documents, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Downstream from Trout Fishing in America, Printer's MS, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Downstream from Trout Fishing in America, Proofs, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Adler, Jack
    - Consumer's Guide to Travel, Correspondence, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Consumer's Guide to Travel, MS, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 15-16)
    - Consumer's Guide to Travel, MS for typesetter, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Consumer's Guide to Travel, Proofs, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Consumer's Guide to Travel, Proofs with corrections, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Akmakjian, Hiag
    - Snow Falling, Author's galleys, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Snow Falling, Galleys, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Snow Falling, MS, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Snow Falling, MS for printer, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Snow Falling, Page proofs, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Altman, Robert
    - Shortcuts, Final lasers, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Shortcuts, Final proofs, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Shortcuts, Proofs, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Arkatov, James
    - Masters of Music, Correspondence, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - Masters of Music, Photo outtakes, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Masters of Music, Proofs, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 24-25)
  - Asher, Don
    - Back-to-Back #4, Boards, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Back-to-Back #4, Corrected proofs, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Back-to-Back #4, Correspondence, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Back-to-Back #4, MS, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Back-to-Back #4, Page proofs, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Back-to-Back #4, Uncorrected proofs, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Back-to-Back #4, Unmarked galleys, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Babb, Sanora
    - The Dark Earth, Correspondence and MS, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - The Dark Earth, MS, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - The Dark Earth, Printout, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Baker, Will
    - Dawn Stone, MS and cover design, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Barbeau, Clayton C.
    - Dante and Gentucca, MS and proofs, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Bass, Rick
    - On Camp Robbers and other works, Correspondence, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - On Camp Robbers and other works, Photo negatives, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Bauersfeld, Marjorie
    - The Afternoon of Me, Proofs, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Beagle, Peter S.
    - Lila the Werewolf, Paste-ups for second edition, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Lila the Werewolf, Proofs and illustrations, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Beaumont, Glass
    - Lotte Lehmann, Correspondence, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Lotte Lehmann, MS, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 2-4)
    - Lotte Lehmann, Photos, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Benson, Robert
    - Great Winemasters of California, Artwork, 1977 (Box 60, Folder Unknown)
    - Great Winemasters of California, Edited MS, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
    - Great Winemasters of California, Galley proof, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Great Winemasters of California, Labels, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Great Winemasters of California, MS draft, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Great Winemasters of California, Page proofs, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Great Winemasters of California, Paste-ups, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 6-7)
    - Great Winemasters of California, Photographs and negatives, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Great Winemasters of California, Working dummy, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Great Winemasters of California, Xerox MS, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Benton, William
    - Eye la View, MS and artwork, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Bernstein, Charles
    - The Joy of Birding, Artwork, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - The Joy of Birding, Correspondence, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - The Joy of Birding, MS, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - The Joy of Birding, Page proofs, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - The Joy of Birding, Proofs, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Bohn, David
    - Backcountry, Dummy, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Backcountry, Galleys and proofs, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Backcountry, MS, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Backcountry, Photos, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - House of Three Turkeys, Artwork, 1977 (Box 60, Folder Unknown)
    - House of Three Turkeys, Galley proofs, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - House of Three Turkeys, MS, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - House of Three Turkeys, Page proofs, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Rambles, Dummies, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Rambles, Galleys, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Rambles, Illustrations, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Rambles, Misc., 1979 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Rambles, MS, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Rambles, Page proofs, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 22-23)
    - Rambles, Test prints, 1979 (Box 58, Folder Unknown)
    - The Capra Chapbook Anthology, foreward, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - The Capra Chapbook Anthology, MS copy and revisions, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Boudreau, Eugene
    - Trails of the Sierra Madre, Artwork, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Trails of the Sierra Madre, Book design material, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Trails of the Sierra Madre, Galleys, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Trails of the Sierra Madre, Illustration, 1973 (Box 58, Folder Unknown)
    - Trails of the Sierra Madre, MS, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Trails of the Sierra Madre, Page proof, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Boyle, Kay
    - Gentlemen, Correspondence, 1990 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Gentlemen, Page proofs, 1990 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Gentlemen, Revised MS, 1990 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Bradbury, Ray
    - Zen and the Art of Writing, Proofs and artwork, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
  - Brand, Max
    - Project, Correspondence, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - The Smoking Land, Agreements, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - The Smoking Land, Miscellaneous, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - The Smoking Land, MS, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - The Smoking Land, Unbound sheets, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Brock, Edwin
    - I Never Saw it Lit, Engraver's proof, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - I Never Saw it Lit, MS, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - I Never Saw it Lit, Page proof, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Bronfen, Nan
    - Nutrition for a Better Life, Book design and promo materials, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Nutrition for a Better Life, Corrected MS pages, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Nutrition for a Better Life, Drafts, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Nutrition for a Better Life, Miscellaneous, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Nutrition for a Better Life, Printer's MS, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 11-14)
    - Nutrition for a Better Life, Proofs, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 16-17)
  - Brown, James Dale
    - The Sudden Disappearance of Japan, Book design materials, 1994 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - The Sudden Disappearance of Japan, Correspondence, 1994 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - The Sudden Disappearance of Japan, Printers proofs, 1994 (Box 54, Folder 4)